Joanne CHEVALIER - Java Developer

320E 46TH Street New York, NY 10017

Phone: (203) 570-8368 - E-Mail: joanne.chevalier@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/joannechevalier/

Summary

I am a passionate **full-stack software engineer**. I love learning new languages and frameworks and can be a strong asset to a team that is based on collaboration and creativity.

I obtained my master's degree in France in 2011 and started to work right after as a Java EE developer in Paris. Last year I got my **Spring Core Specification**.

Paris is a great Tech city but I always wanted to experience the New York's work culture, so I moved here to discover new opportunities.

For the last 5 years I've been working on the e-commerce web applications of big companies like Accor or Dior. For example my last project at Dior.com was developing a REST service for the brand new checkout funnel with Java/Spring.

My experience is mostly a back-end experience. I develop with Java, Spring, Tomcat, Maven, JSP, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Hibernate ...etc. But I also have a good front-end experience with HTML5/CSS3/Javascript, Twitter Bootstrap, JQuery and AngularJS.

On the side, I try to keep learning, taking classes on Coursera.com, currently I am attending a **NodeJS/MongoDB** course. And I also develop a **RESTful back-office application** for a Bed & Breakfast in France with Dropwizard and AngularJS.

Today I am looking for a **full-stack position**, **which** offers opportunities to develop my skills and learn new ones. I am not very comfortable with competition; instead I prefer environments of **collaboration**, **mutual respect**, and with opportunities for **learning**, **creativity**, and **mentorship**.

I am a very good team player, familiar with Agile Methodologies such as Scrum, TDD, Kanban, etc.

Experience

October 2014 - October 2015 (1 year)

Java Web Developer at Dior (LVMH) - Paris, France

Developing the Dior Fragrance and Beauty e-commerce website in a team of 5 developers

- Development of the Dior's new checkout funnel for 3 markets (Japan, USA, France)
- Back Office and Front Office development
- Desktop and mobile versions
- Corrective and evolutive maintenance

Skills: Java, Spring, Spring MVC, Velocity, Open JPA, HTML/CSS, JSON, Tomcat, Apache, Subversion

April 2012 - October 2014 (2 years 6 months)

Java Web Developer at Accor - Paris, France

Development of the Offers and Promotions of Accorhotels.com domain and its 14 hotel brands in 31 geo-localized versions and 16 languages, in a team of 7 to 9 developers.

■ Development of the Offers and Promotions contribution interface (Back Office) - CMS/Web

Joanne CHEVALIER - Java Developer

320E 46TH Street New York, NY 10017

Phone: (203) 570-8368 E-Mail: joanne.chevalier@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/joannechevalier/

- Responsible for the development and redesign projects of Pullman, Sofitel, Le Club AccorHotels, Mercure
 and Ibis brands (Requirements gathering, Design Documents and Technical Specifications writing, Costs
 estimation, Back Office and Front Office development)
- Migration project to a new CMS: Oracle WebCenter Sites (Gathered requirements for the migration, Wrote Detailed Technical Specifications, Supervised the software developments and managed the testing returns)

Skills: Java, JSP, JSTL, Wedia CrossMedia CMS, HTML/CSS/Javascript, XML, JSON, Tomcat, Apache, CVS

September 2011 - April 2012 (8 months)

Java Web Developer at Editions Weka - Paris, France

Project «Méridien» of Techniques de l'Ingénieur website in a team of 4 developers

- Graphical and ergonomic overhaul
- Redesign of customers' Intranet (Spring Batch)
- Corrective and evolutive maintenance

Skills: Java, Spring MVC, Spring Batch, PostgreSQL, Freemarker, Hibernate, XHTML / CSS / JQuery

February 2011 - August 2011 (7 months)

Java Web Software Intern, Ippon Technologies - Paris, France

Redesign of the Paris Ile-de-France Regional Chamber of Commerce and Industry portal in a team of 4 developers.

Skills: Java, Scrum, XHTML/CSS, Spring MVC, Velocity, Liferay, JQuery

Education

Université de Pau et des Pays de l'Adour - Pau, France

2009 - 2011

Master's degree, Software Engineering

Including one semester abroad on a student exchange program at Mälardalen University (Västerås, Sweden)

Université de Caen Basse Normandie - Caen, France

2008 - 2009

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

Université de Caen Basse Normandie - Caen, France

2005 - 2008

Bachelor's Degree, Electrical and Electronics Engineering

Certification

Spring Core 3.2 certification

Joanne CHEVALIER - Java Developer

320E 46TH Street New York, NY 10017

Phone: (203) 570-8368 E-Mail: joanne.chevalier@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/joannechevalier/

Skills

Development: Java, Java EE, JUnit, HTML5, CSS3, Apache Velocity, Freemarker, JSP, Javascript

Frameworks: Spring Core, Spring MVC, Spring Security, Hibernate, JPA, AngularJS, JQuery, Bootstrap

Databases: MySQL, PostGreSQL

Operating systems: OSX, Linux, Windows

Others: Scrum, Kanban, Teamwork, Maven, Grunt, Bower, Tomcat, Subversion, CVS, Git

Languages

French: Native

English: Full professional proficiency

Spanish: Elementary proficiency

Volunteer

Meal Kit Packing at New York Cares